<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ADLs | Jiawei Zheng</title>
    <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/tag/adls/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/tag/adls/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>ADLs</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2025 Jiawei Zheng</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 04:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/media/icon_hu88e86d5999bd18f15f6d00205cac0ab3_27282_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>ADLs</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/tag/adls/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Process-aware Pattern Recognition and Deviation Detection Under Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Humans naturally follow specific patterns in their daily activities, whether driven by best practices, physical layouts, social norms or established processes or routines. Monitoring and understanding these human activities is a challenging problem, with the ultimate goal of identifying anomalies from desired behaviour, such as those related to healthy living or efficient working. Recognising process patterns and routines, and  detecting anomalies can provide crucial insights. However, this presents significant challenges across different domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Varying structures of processes in different domains complicate the task of capturing and analysing these patterns, as well as understanding the multifaceted nature of anomalies. Some domains are structured, like manufacturing, therefore it is easier to detect workflow patterns and deviations from them, but others are semi-structured or unstructured, like daily living. In the latter, even defining what an anomaly means is a challenge. Moreover, data are often filled with noise and uncertainties, which may lead to misinterpretation of normal occurrences as anomalies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims to incorporate process information in the domain knowledge to interpret patterns and detect anomalies in different domains.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Successfully defend my PhD thesis with no correction.</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/post/viva/index/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 15:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/post/viva/index/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Successfully defend my PhD thesis with no correction. My PhD thesis is titled as &amp;ldquo;Process-aware Pattern Recognition and Deviation Detection Under Uncertainty&amp;rdquo;. My PhD research focuses on leveraging domain-specific knowledge (processes) to enhance the performance and interpretability of machine learning models and handling uncertain and probabilistic data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Present the work of Process-aware Human Activity Recognition at Multimodal AI workshop.</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/post/multimodalai/index/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/post/multimodalai/index/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I presented the work of &amp;ldquo;Process-aware Human Activity Recognition&amp;rdquo; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://multimodalai.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Multimodal AI workshop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Present our work of probabilistic conformance checking at HICSS conference in Honolulu, Hawaii.</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/post/hicsspresent/index/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 15:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/post/hicsspresent/index/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Present our work of &lt;a href=&#34;https://hdl.handle.net/10125/107104&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;probabilistic conformance checking&lt;/a&gt; at HICSS conference in Honolulu, Hawaii.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give a talk on &#39;&#39;Digital Twin for Assisted Living&#39;&#39; at Xidian University.</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/post/xidiantalk/index/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 15:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/post/xidiantalk/index/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk on &amp;lsquo;Digital Twin for Assisted Living&amp;rsquo; at Xidian University.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give a talk on &#39;&#39;Activities of Daily Living of Older Adults&#39;&#39; at Advanced Care Research Centre.</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/post/usher-talk/index/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 15:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/post/usher-talk/index/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk on &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Activities of Daily Living of Older Adults&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; at Advanced Care Research Centre, Usher Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Present the work of &#39;&#39;Predictive Behavioural Monitoring in Activities of Daily Livings of Older Adults&#39;&#39; at the International Conference on Health Informatics (HealthINF).</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/post/healthinf/index/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 15:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/post/healthinf/index/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I presented the paper titled &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Predictive Behavioural Monitoring and Deviation Detection in Activities of Daily Livings of Older Adults&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; at the International Conference on Health Informatics (HealthINF).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk in DigiFest2021: Proactive health monitoring based on Activities of Daily Living</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/post/digifest2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 15:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/post/digifest2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This talk focused on an onging project. This is aimed at exploiting sensor data on Activities of Daily Living (ADLs) to detect deviations and deterioration from a healthy routine. We also use our models to investigate the realtionship between sleep duration and other activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Care &amp; Research Center (ACRC)</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/acrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/acrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This research programme will develop practical, care-driven technologies that are fit for people in later life. In particular, this means exploring and developing data-driven IoT platforms that can produce accurate data about instant events (e.g. vital signs and serious incidents such as falls), short-term activities (e.g. those of daily living) and long-term pursuits (e.g. physical and mental activities over weeks and months) in order to extract (predictive) information and patterns that can be used, among other things, for effective interventions and the prevention of adverse outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will develop digitised models of care to allow for meaningful understanding and decision support. This includes models that capture knowledge about care pathways, guidelines, and practices, as well as individual needs and circumstances. These will be used to inform the new models of care work package. Explainable models using AI on existing data to produce alerts and insights towards meaningful interventions. Finally, we will use these digital models to provide predictive performance measures under different circumstances and ageing population trends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
