<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ADLs | Jiawei Zheng</title>
    <link>https://jw2heng.github.io/tag/adls/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jw2heng.github.io/tag/adls/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>ADLs</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Jiawei Zheng</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jw2heng.github.io/media/icon_hu88e86d5999bd18f15f6d00205cac0ab3_27282_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>ADLs</title>
      <link>https://jw2heng.github.io/tag/adls/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk in DigiFest2021: Proactive health monitoring based on Activities of Daily Living</title>
      <link>https://jw2heng.github.io/post/digifest2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jw2heng.github.io/post/digifest2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Care &amp; Research Center (ACRC)</title>
      <link>https://jw2heng.github.io/project/acrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jw2heng.github.io/project/acrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This research programme will develop practical, care-driven technologies that are fit for people in later life. In particular, this means exploring and developing data-driven IoT platforms that can produce accurate data about instant events (e.g. vital signs and serious incidents such as falls), short-term activities (e.g. those of daily living) and long-term pursuits (e.g. physical and mental activities over weeks and months) in order to extract (predictive) information and patterns that can be used, among other things, for effective interventions and the prevention of adverse outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will develop digitised models of care to allow for meaningful understanding and decision support. This includes models that capture knowledge about care pathways, guidelines, and practices, as well as individual needs and circumstances. These will be used to inform the new models of care work package. Explainable models using AI on existing data to produce alerts and insights towards meaningful interventions. Finally, we will use these digital models to provide predictive performance measures under different circumstances and ageing population trends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
