<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Jiawei Zheng</title>
    <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2025 Jiawei Zheng</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 04:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/media/icon_hu88e86d5999bd18f15f6d00205cac0ab3_27282_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>LLM-powered Digital Innovation and Transformation for Enterprises</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/llm-dt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/llm-dt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project explores how large language models (LLMs) can support enterprise-level digital transformation by acting as intelligent consulting agents. Funded by the UK Research and Innovation (UKRI) DigitLab programme, our system provides practical tools for assessing digital maturity, identifying transformation needs, and generating tailored recommendations — all powered by state-of-the-art LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-overview&#34;&gt;Project overview:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We developed a modular, multi-agent framework that leverages LLMs to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conduct semi-structured interviews with domain experts using interactive LLM-powered agents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collect, summarize, and analyze client responses in real time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate professional-grade reports with contextual understanding and consistency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate and score reports automatically across different use cases (e.g., healthcare, manufacturing, consulting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-features&#34;&gt;Key Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LLM-based Consulting Agents&lt;/strong&gt;: Autonomous agents capable of conducting interviews, eliciting information, and adapting to user inputs across sessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Context Tracking &amp;amp; Memory Augmentation&lt;/strong&gt;: Maintains coherent, goal-driven conversations with memory-aware dialogue management and summarization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RAG-Enhanced Responses&lt;/strong&gt;: Retrieval-Augmented Generation pipeline to ground responses in enterprise-specific knowledge and domain context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated Report Evaluation&lt;/strong&gt;: Multi-agent evaluation system that analyzes generated reports and flags missing, inconsistent, or misaligned content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gradio-based Data Annotation Tool&lt;/strong&gt;: A user-friendly UI for collecting preference data from consulting experts, used for feedback collection and fine-tuning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;research--collaboration&#34;&gt;Research &amp;amp; Collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is part of the UKRI-funded &lt;a href=&#34;https://digit.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DigitLab&lt;/a&gt; programme and conducted in collaboration with business and operational researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered Image and Video Generation with ComfyUI</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/comfyui/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/comfyui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project leverages the ComfyUI platform to explore and implement a variety of AI models for image and video generation. By integrating state-of-the-art generative models, e.g., Flux, Stable Diffusion, etc., the project aims to create a user-friendly workflow for producing high-quality visuals, enabling artists, developers, and enthusiasts to generate content effortlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-Model Integration: Utilize a diverse set of AI models (e.g., Stable Diffusion, SDXL, ControlNet, and others) to generate both static images and dynamic videos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ComfyUI Workflow Optimization: Design modular and efficient workflows within ComfyUI to adapt usecases and enhance usability, customization, and scalability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image Generation: Generate highly detailed and realistic images based on text prompts, sketches, and style-guided inputs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video Generation: Implement AI-driven video synthesis methods, enabling smooth transitions, frame interpolation, and AI-powered animations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customization &amp;amp; Control: Provide users with fine-tuned settings for resolution, style transfer, depth mapping, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation &amp;amp; Scripting: Enable batch processing, API integrations, and automation features for streamlined creative workflows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potential Use Cases&lt;/strong&gt;：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital Art &amp;amp; Design: Artists and designers can create unique visuals effortlessly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video Content Creation: AI-powered video generation for animations, ads, and visual storytelling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Game &amp;amp; VR Development: Generate textures, assets, and immersive AI-driven content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marketing &amp;amp; Branding: Businesses can create eye-catching media content for campaigns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Process-aware Pattern Recognition and Deviation Detection Under Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Humans naturally follow specific patterns in their daily activities, whether driven by best practices, physical layouts, social norms or established processes or routines. Monitoring and understanding these human activities is a challenging problem, with the ultimate goal of identifying anomalies from desired behaviour, such as those related to healthy living or efficient working. Recognising process patterns and routines, and  detecting anomalies can provide crucial insights. However, this presents significant challenges across different domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Varying structures of processes in different domains complicate the task of capturing and analysing these patterns, as well as understanding the multifaceted nature of anomalies. Some domains are structured, like manufacturing, therefore it is easier to detect workflow patterns and deviations from them, but others are semi-structured or unstructured, like daily living. In the latter, even defining what an anomaly means is a challenge. Moreover, data are often filled with noise and uncertainties, which may lead to misinterpretation of normal occurrences as anomalies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims to incorporate process information in the domain knowledge to interpret patterns and detect anomalies in different domains.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Care &amp; Research Center (ACRC)</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/acrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/acrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This research programme will develop practical, care-driven technologies that are fit for people in later life. In particular, this means exploring and developing data-driven IoT platforms that can produce accurate data about instant events (e.g. vital signs and serious incidents such as falls), short-term activities (e.g. those of daily living) and long-term pursuits (e.g. physical and mental activities over weeks and months) in order to extract (predictive) information and patterns that can be used, among other things, for effective interventions and the prevention of adverse outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will develop digitised models of care to allow for meaningful understanding and decision support. This includes models that capture knowledge about care pathways, guidelines, and practices, as well as individual needs and circumstances. These will be used to inform the new models of care work package. Explainable models using AI on existing data to produce alerts and insights towards meaningful interventions. Finally, we will use these digital models to provide predictive performance measures under different circumstances and ageing population trends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trusted and controlled sharing technology and system of multi-domain IoT based on blockchain</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/blockchain-province/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/blockchain-province/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The aim of this research programme is below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solving information isolation resulting from vertical IoT applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establishing cross-domain authentication and access control mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designing and developing data sharing and exchanging system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent service transaction operation mechanism and performance optimization technology</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/blockchain-national/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/blockchain-national/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project aims to develope a intelligent service trasaction system based on crowd sourcing and blockchain technologiee so that it can meet the requirements of high performance and supervision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, we develope a service-oriented and high-precision service publishing and composition system. This enables end-users (e.g., individuals and companies) to publish their services and data in the blockchain as digital asset. This could also provide high-precision service recommendation and service composition regarding to the custimized functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also investigate the approaches to improve the performance of blockchain by optimizing the consensus algorithms and sharding techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A blockchain-based service trading mechanism and system is developed to enable decentralized services transactions on blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive IoT access and service delivery platform and demonstration application</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/iot-province/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/iot-province/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This research programme aims to realize these research goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realizing adaptive access for heterogeneous IoT devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designing distribute computing and data storage architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing demonstration IoT application in industrial field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
