<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blockchain | Jiawei Zheng</title>
    <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/tag/blockchain/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/tag/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blockchain</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2025 Jiawei Zheng</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/media/icon_hu88e86d5999bd18f15f6d00205cac0ab3_27282_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Blockchain</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/tag/blockchain/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trusted and controlled sharing technology and system of multi-domain IoT based on blockchain</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/blockchain-province/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/blockchain-province/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The aim of this research programme is below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solving information isolation resulting from vertical IoT applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establishing cross-domain authentication and access control mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designing and developing data sharing and exchanging system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent service transaction operation mechanism and performance optimization technology</title>
      <link>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/blockchain-national/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jia-wei-zheng.github.io/project/blockchain-national/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project aims to develope a intelligent service trasaction system based on crowd sourcing and blockchain technologiee so that it can meet the requirements of high performance and supervision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, we develope a service-oriented and high-precision service publishing and composition system. This enables end-users (e.g., individuals and companies) to publish their services and data in the blockchain as digital asset. This could also provide high-precision service recommendation and service composition regarding to the custimized functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also investigate the approaches to improve the performance of blockchain by optimizing the consensus algorithms and sharding techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A blockchain-based service trading mechanism and system is developed to enable decentralized services transactions on blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
